{
    "id": "92dbbd01b73b4b148189c6c780aa0bcd",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "………………………. up, the thief ran away.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get:\r\nThe thief jumped up. He ran away. We can connect them with the present participle jumping.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Jumped",
                "Jumping",
                "Having jumping"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… he sat down to rest.",
            "description": "When we split the clauses we get:\r\nHe was tired. He sat down to rest.\r\nWe can combine them using being tired.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Tiring",
                "Having tired",
                "Being tired"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "William I defeated Harold …………………… was the successor of Edward the Confessor in",
            "description": "We use who to refer to people. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This town ……………………….. was once a prosperous sea-port is now a heap of ruins.",
            "description": "We use which to refer to places and things.",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "which",
                "who"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The young woman fainted ………………….. hearing the news of her husband’s death.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "at",
                "on",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The police ………………………, the mob dispersed.",
            "description": "The two clauses are:\r\nThe police arrived. The mob dispersed. Here the clauses have different subjects. We can connect them using ‘having arrived’.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "arriving",
                "arrived",
                "having arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… his foot, he stopped.",
            "description": "He hurt his foot. He stopped. We can combine them using 'having hurt'.",
            "answers": [
                "Being hurt",
                "Having hurt",
                "Hurt"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The cow provides milk ………………………… is a nutritious food.",
            "description": "We use which to refer to things.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "what",
                "who"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "His uncle ………………………. was a millionaire sent him to England for higher studies.",
            "description": "That is not used in non-identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "whom",
                "who",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Chaucer ………………………… was the first great English poet was born in",
            "description": "That is not used in non-identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody knows ………………………… Homer, the great poet, was born.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "where",
                "there",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………. does not work must starve.",
            "description": "Only who can replace pronouns like he and she.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}